Kunal Mehra

🗣 Gurugram, Harayana 🛮 🗷 kunalmehra 240304@gmail.com 📞 +91 93290 37858 🛭 in LinkedIn 💢 Github 🌐 kunalmehra 075. github.io

As a **Full Stack Web Developer** with nearly **2 years** of experience in the **MERN** stack, I am dedicated to writing production-ready code that is both effective and unique. Valuing **skills** over formal degrees, I aim to bring innovative solutions to the IT world. I am seeking opportunities to contribute to a team where I can drive success for both myself and the organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript | TypeScript | Python | React | React Native | Node.js | Express | REST APIs | MongoDB | MySQL | Redis
- System Design | AWS | GCP | Oauth | WebSockets | Docker | Serverless | Kubernetes | Jenkins | Firebase
- Tailwind CSS | Chakra/Material UI | Redux Toolkit | Selenium | Playwright | Sonarqube | Unit Testing | Integration Testing

EXPERIENCE

86 Agency (Software Engineer)

Gurugram, IND June 2023- Present

- Worked on over 20+ web applications using React, Node, and MongoDB, leveraging multiple UI libraries and many technologies to handle complex CRUD operations with appropriate code quality and readability.
- Collaborated with 3 international clients, creating APIs, resolving complex issues in their codebases, and integrating
 Apple and Google Passes into mobile wallets with notification management.
- Worked on a design system using Shadon and Storybook, and developed a user contract management backend.
- Single-handedly completed the wallet integration project in just 2 months, when the initial plan was to last for 4 months
- Created a video call app with React Native, featuring chat, calendar events, and live chat with Websockets.
- Managed over 15 web applications on AWS, utilizing Docker, performing health checks, addressing security and vulnerability aspects, code reviews, and implementing CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins.

Pesto Fellowship, Pesto Tech (Engineering Fellow)

San Francisco, USA (Remote) July 2023- Present

- A 10-month-long program based on the MERN stack to improve the core concepts & build market-ready products.
- Led a team of 5 in designing and developing a comprehensive Hospital Management System.
- Collaborated with tech industry professionals to discuss and solve complex technical issues based on real-life problems.

PROJECTS & MILESTONES

<u>MyCal</u>

Github 💭 Link 🔗

- Developed Calendly clone, an Events/Calendar Management web service, with live event booking and calendar display.
- Designed the whole backend and APIs. Also implemented Google Auth, email notifications, workflows, and reminders.
- Built using React, Node.js, and MongoDB, in a collaborative group of 5 members over 6 days..

Ace Legal Services

Github C Link

- Crafted an online lawyers' appointment booking system, along with 5 team members over 7 days.
- Enabled clients to book appointments, login/signup, OTP password reset, email notifications & reminders.
- Implemented more than 70% of CRUD operations using React, Ant Design, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.

Orangefry.com

Github 💢 Link 🔗

- Constructed a UI/UX-enhanced clone of Pepperfry.com, a furniture and home decor selling web service.
- Enabled users to buy, and provided admin functionality to manage products, users, and comments.
- Forged using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB as an individual project in 6 days.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Web Development, Masai School

Bengaluru, IND August 2022 - May 2023

- Learned front-end development, React, Typescript, data structures, and algorithms, and specialized in backend development with Node.is, Express, server-side programming, system design, and databases.
- Gained proficiency in React, spending 1200 hours coding real-time web applications and solving 800+ DSA problems.
- Dedicated 200 hours to holistic development, focusing on teamwork, remote collaboration, and project contribution skills.

Higher Secondary Education

Jabalpur, IND July 2020 - March 2022

• St. Joseph Convent Sr. School Jabalpur, MP

ADDITIONALS

Soft Skills: Leadership, Strong Communication, Adapting, Problem-Solving & Remote Collaboration.

Hobbies: Playing Guitar, Football, Events & Hackathons Languages: English, Hindi